# **ANNELISE SMITH** [ PROGRAM MANAGER ]

annelisesmithux@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a program manager and user researcher with a background in design, human/organizational development, and prevention science. I work with engineers, designers, researchers, to solve complex technical, operational, and interpersonal challenges. I use the power of storytelling to help teams keep the bigger picture in mind while still being meticulous and detail-oriented. I take pride in building genuine, authentic connections to build consensus and motivate others to deliver their best work.

### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## **User Studies Program Coordinator** at Facebook Reality Labs *Redmond, WA (Mar 2018 - present)*

- >Provide end-to-end user study coordination for 25+ user studies while managing assignments for a team of 20 Research Assistants.
- >Partner with research teams, Legal, Health & Safety, Comms, and external vendors to write, submit, maintain, and disseminate regulatory and best practices documentation.
- >Design and implement processes for participant recruitment, scheduling, and payment and maintain communication with participant recruitment vendors.
- >Create and disseminate org-wide onboarding, training, continuing education modules, and documentation for all research assistants and interns.
- >Provide timely communication and reporting with senior research management regarding study statuses, resource allocation, and operational blockers/issues.

## Research Assistant at Oculus Research Redmond, WA (Aug 2017 - Mar 2018)

- >Worked with research scientists, engineers, and designers to set-up and facilitate human factors and applied perception science user studies involving confidential AR/VR headset prototypes and other technical equipment.
- >Coordinated recruitment and scheduling of external and internal study participants.
- >Wrote and implemented accessible study protocols and user recruitment plans to increase diversity and representation in our participant demographics

## **User Experience Design Instructor** at General Assembly *Seattle, WA (Jan 2016 - Jan 2018)*

- >Led the development of specialized workshops and courses in user research, mobile design, persona creation, journey mapping, and diversity issues in tech.
- >Conducted one-on-one and group design critiques and feedback sessions
- >Updated and designed new curriculum to align with industry/educational best practices
- >Developed and organized a campus-wide hackathon with 55+ participants.

## **Experiential Marketing Lead** at Freelance *Seattle, WA (Oct 2015 - Aug 2016)*

>Developed, organized, and oversaw the execution of experiential marketing campaigns to drive product awareness and foster brand loyalty.

# **Program Manager** at Communities in Schools of Lakewood *Lakewood*, WA (Aug 2013 - Aug 2014)

- >Collaborated with student, family, school, and community stakeholders to identify core student needs and secure community-level resources for at-risk, low-income students.
- >Led recruitment, retention, training, and management of 59 program staff/volunteers

### TOOLS/SKILLS

Sketch, InVision, MS Office, Adobe Illustrator, Google Analytics, E-learning Design, User Journey Mapping, Personas, Conflict Mediation, Training Facilitation

### **EDUCATION**

#### **UX Design Immersive**

General Assembly Seattle, WA 2016

### MA in Human Development

Washington State University Prevention Science Focus 2013

#### **BA in Social Sciences**

Washington State University Minor in Ethnic Studies Minor in German 2011

### OTHER EXPERIENCE

**UX Designer & Researcher** Freelance Oct 2016 - Aug 2017

### Child Abuse Investigator and Forensic Interviewer

WA Child Protective Services Aug 2014 - Oct 2015

#### Research Manager

Washington State University Aug 2011 - Aug 2013

#### Cultural Competency Training Lead

Washington State University Aug 2012 - Nov 2013